Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

□ (+84) 168 4643 181 | 💌 nguyentrucxinh@outlook.com | 🏕 nguyentrucxinh.github.io | 🖸 nguyentrucxinh | 🗖 nguyentrucxinh

"Built tools to help human solve problems."

Summary_

JavaScript junkie and Java lover. Current Java Developer at outsourcing company Sutrix Group. 2+ years experience specializing in both backend and frontend development. Interested in learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. Favorite stacks: Node.js/React/MongoDB - JavaEE/Spring/Hibernate. Mostly.

Education

HUTECH (Ho Chi Minh University of Technology)

BIT - BACHELOR OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Oct. 2012 - Oct. 2016

Work Experience _____

Sutrix Group

JAVA WEB DEVELOPER

Aug. 2017 - PRESENT

- Design and implement RESTful APIs
- · Write high-quality code (Java) that communicates with upstream backend services via HTTP APIs
- Identify and resolve performance and scalability issues
- Build high-quality web apps/services by writing clean and modular code
- Improve reliability of web apps/services through bug fixes
- · Design, build, analyze and fix large-scale systems
- · Work on special projects as needed
- · Other duties as assigned

Software Company Tin Tan. Co., Ltd.

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER Mar. 2016 - Jul. 2017

- Develop a deep understanding of our system and suggest UI improvements proactively
- · Work effectively as a team member of the development team
- · Deliver milestones on time
- Participate in design the project and code review.
- Review business requirements working with team members
- Perform a technical analysis of requirements
- Produce a solid, detailed technical design
- Write clean, modular, robust code to implement the desired requirements with little or no supervision
- Contribute ideas for making the application better and easier to use
- Ensure on time, on the budget, and the quality of the product.
- · Proactively learn product frameworks and code base
- Analyze requirements and design solutions
- Research new technologies
- Commitment to high code quality and delivery requirements

Projects_____

TechBridge Market (Team size: 14 members)

Aug. 2017 - Present

KEY MEMBER

- · Java SE/EE
- · Spring Boot / Spring MVC
- Hibernate
- Maven
- MySQL
- Google Cloud Platform / Google App Engine
- Design Patterns
- Microservices
- · Web Services
- RESTful APIs / SOAP
- JWT / OAuth2
- 3rd Party: TextKernel, BroadBean

Transport Management & Vending Machine Management (Team size: 3 members)

Sep. 2016 - Jul. 2017

LEADER & KEY MEMBER

- PHP 7 / Laravel 5.4
- Angular 4 / TypeScript 2
- MySQL 5.7
- Bootstrap 3
- Web Services / RESTful APIs / JWT
- Design Patterns: IoC/DI, Repository, Singleton, Observer

Clinic Management (Team size: 5 members)

MEMBER

- C#
- · Windows Forms
- DevExpress
- MSSQL

Skills

Languages: Vietnamese (Native), English

Tech skills:

- JavaScript ES5 & ES6 (1y5m)
- Node.js/Express.js
- MongoDB/Mongoose
- React/Redux
- Angular/TypeScript (1y5m)
- Microservices (1y)
- Java SE/EE (1y)
- Spring/Hibernate (1y)
- PHP/Laravel (1y5m)
- JIRA (1y)
- Coding Convertions
- Web services: REST/SOAP (2y)

- Authentication: JWT/OAuth2 (2y)
- PaaS: Google Cloud Platform, Heroku (1y)
- Version control: Git (2y)
- DBMS: MySQL, MSSQL (2y)
- HTML/CSS/jQuery/Bootstrap/Pug
- Principles: SOLID, DRY, KISS, YAGNI
- Design Patterns
- · Object-Oriented Programming
- · Functional Programming
- Reactive Programming
- Photoshop (Basic)

Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2016